Imagine sitting down for dinner in ancient Babylon.
想象一下在古代巴比伦坐下来吃晚餐。
What would be on the menu?
菜单上会有什么？
Thanks to clay tablets discovered over a century ago, we're starting to find out.
多亏了一个多世纪前发现的泥板，我们开始找到答案。
These tablets, written around 4,000 years ago, were originally thought to be about medicine.
这些泥板写于大约4000年前，最初被认为与医学有关。
But in the 1980s, scholars realised that these texts were actually recipes.
但在20世纪80年代，学者们意识到这些文本实际上是食谱。"
"Out of hundreds of thousands of cuneiform documents, they are the only food recipes that exist" says Agnete Lassen, associate curator of the Yale Babylonian collection.
在数十万份楔形文字文献中，它们是仅存的食物食谱，"耶鲁大学巴比伦藏品馆副馆长阿格尼特·拉森说。
This means they offer a rare glimpse into the culinary world of this ancient region of Mesopotamia, now modern-day Iraq.
这意味着它们为人们了解美索不达米亚（今伊拉克境内）这一古代地区的烹饪世界提供了一个难得的机会。
It seems the cooks of that time were expected to know what they were doing – the instructions are straight to the point, and the amounts of the ingredients are not specified.
看来当时的厨师知道自己应该怎么做——说明简单直接，食材的用量也没有具体说明。
Despite this, modern researchers have been recreating and taste-testing the ancient dishes.
尽管如此，现代研究人员一直在重现和品尝这些古代菜肴。
One recipe that has been successfully recreated is a stew called 'tuh'u'.
一道成功复原的菜肴是一种名为"tuh'u"的炖菜。
The dish starts with water and seared lamb. Then, in go salt, beer, some vegetables, and for a fiery taste, garlic and coriander.
这道菜以水和煎羊肉开始，然后加入盐、啤酒、一些蔬菜，以及为了增添辣味而加入的大蒜和香菜。
It's a favourite among researchers: "It's pungent and it's very nicely spiced" says Agnete Lassen, "It has good flavours."
这是研究人员的最爱："味道浓郁，调味非常好，"阿格尼特·拉森说，"它的味道很好。"
Another dish turned out so unbearably bitter that none of the other seasonings could be detected, so either the translation was incorrect, or people's tastes were very different back then.
另一道菜的味道却苦得令人难以忍受，以至于尝不出任何其他调味料的味道，所以要么是翻译有误，要么是当时人们的口味与现在大相径庭。
Interestingly, all the recipes discovered are for making stews and broths, observes Iraqi food historian, Nawal Nasrallah.
有趣的是，伊拉克美食历史学家纳瓦尔·纳斯鲁拉观察到，所有被发现的食谱都是关于制作炖菜和肉汤的。
Stew remained a tradition in medieval Iraq and continues to be a staple of modern Iraqi food.
炖菜在中世纪的伊拉克仍是一种传统，并继续成为现代伊拉克食物的主食。
On the other hand, other ancient flavours have disappeared.
另一方面，其他古代风味已经消失了。
For example, a Roman fish sauce called 'garam' was a potent, fermented sauce with an umami flavour.
例如，一种名为"garam"的罗马鱼露，是一种带有鲜味的强力发酵酱汁。
It was once popular but is now not a common feature of modern Italian cuisine.
它曾经很受欢迎，但现在已不是现代意大利菜中的常见特色。
How many of our own culinary traditions will survive years from now?
我们自己的烹饪传统有多少能存续多年？
Will future generations taste what we taste today, or will our favourite dishes become forgotten?
后代能品尝到我们今天品尝的味道吗，还是我们最喜欢的菜肴会被遗忘？